And it's so readable with camel case.
>> No, it's way more readable with
underscores. You're so used to reading
with spaces.
>> But but it's I don't
>> I'm a Python bro. And we got to name all
our functions with underscores.
>> Don't freaking tell me you're a Python
bro. I am a Python bro.
>> Best part of hacking when you can just
critical think.
Yeah, dude.
>> All right, guys. You know the drill.
This is the segment of the show where we
typically do an ad, but today we got
something different for you, and it's an
exciting announcement that we are
launching the critical thinking pentest
group. Okay. Um, we have an amazingly
talented group of hackers that live in
the CTVBB Discord and in the community
um that we're so grateful to be able to
work with. And we have a spec particular
niche of that called the full-time
hunters guild. Um, these are people that
are validated to have performed very
high level in Pug Bounty. Um, and we are
going to be performing pen tests uh for
you the listener. if you guys have a
scope that you want to be tested. Um,
ourselves, meaning me, Reszo, Gretme,
me, other members of the CTBB team, and
pulling highly qualified members that
are aligned with your scope specifically
from the full-time hunters guild to also
do uh penetration testing as required.
Um, so we're going to make sure with all
the hackers that we have access to that
the hackers that are working on your
scope are extremely qualified in exactly
what you would like to have tested,
right? Because we're pulling from a big
group of people. Um, so if you're
interested in that and you think your
organization could benefit from that,
check out pentest.ctb.show.
It's going to be a lot of fun. We're
going to tear stuff up. It's going to be
amazing. Um, so yeah, drop us a line if
you're interested. Um, and then the
second piece here is, of course, I want
to remind you we do have the full-time
hunters guild available. So if you are a
hunter that is out there and is killing
it and wants to be among other high
performing hunters, this is the place to
do it. Okay? ctvb.showftthg
FTHG for full-time hunters guild. Go
ahead and apply if you meet the
criteria. Um, and you'll get access to
not only a highc caliber community, but
also opportunities like the pentest uh,
opportunities that we have coming
through critical thinking. So, lots of
exciting stuff going on. Um, excited to
work with you guys if you think you
could benefit from some pentest or if
you want to join the full-time Hunters
Guild community. All right, I'll see you
there. Peace.
Sup, hackers. got the this week in bug
bounty segment for you before we hop
into the episode. Um the first item on
the list today is a article by Yes We
Hack entitled cost AI frontier models
and more a measure take on the future of
security testing. And as we've been
talking a ton on the pod recently about
you know what is the future of bug
bounty? What is the future of uh
continuous security testing as we know
it? There are a lot of takes and there
are a lot of different opinions floating
around. So I think it's really important
to get a bunch of different
perspectives. So, uh, I'd recommend you
go ahead and read this article, um, and
get a little bit more data, uh, in. And
we've also got another article from, uh,
Integrity, uh, that we'll link in the
description as well called Common AI
misconceptions debugged. Okay. Um, and
this is also sort of talking about the
way that AI is affecting the industry.
So, two really good articles, one from
Yes We Hack, one from Integrity on it.
Um a quick takeaway that I had from the
integrity one was this right here which
is um uh validity ratios remain constant
even though the volume has been
increased dramatically
uh across bug bounty at this point right
from 2022 to 2025 submissions grew 328%.
Um and we're going to see that I'm sure
even more this year um with with uh AI
becoming more prolific.
Um, but that does mean a lot of more
valid reports, too. So, we're just
getting a lot of volume. Um, and we got
to figure out how to how to sort it out.
Um, so those are some articles for you
to take a look at. Uh, last but not
least, we have a Bounty Sync Plus Social
event uh that is being held by Integrity
in uh the UK in London. That's Thursday,
May 21st. We're going to link that uh
down below. But that seems like a good
opportunity to connect with people in
the London area um in the in the Bug
Bounty world. So, if you're in the UK,
uh definitely check this out if you're
near London and can make it over for
this event. Thursday, May 21st um in
London. Uh all right, I think that's it
for the Twib. Let's go to the show.
>> Dude, so I step away for one week and
you put out a Doomer episode, bro.
>> Listen, I did a I did an awesome ad
read. I made a custom thumbnail. I
carried a good episode.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Jason. I
appreciate it.
>> You're right, though. It was a little
bit of a doomer episode.
>> It was a little bit of a doomer episode,
man. Um, and I feel you. I feel you. It
is concerning. I'm not going to lie. The
the landscape is concerning right now.
>> Hey, I know you probably want to jump to
other stuff, but it's on the I'm
actually going to do it right now. I'm
going to share my screen here.
>> All right. I made a since we're talking
about the last episode, I made a
image to represent what I was talking
about.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. What is this?
>> I really think that this
>> funnel why Bug Bounty is dying. What the
heck, bro? This is a Bug Bounty podcast.
>> Yeah, I know. But anyways, listen, the
point is this is what people need to be
concerned about and it's what they need
to push against. This is why they need
to adapt and evolve and go deeper and
incorporate AI into their hacking. But
uh yeah, I feel like that I kind of
explained it well, but the point I was
trying to get across was this basically,
right? Is that AI written code's
probably going to get better. There's
going to be AI code review, internal
hackbot testing filters more, and then
when you get down here, you got to
compete with the sharks with the likes
of me, hence the shark.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, yeah. Anyways,
>> the the superpowered shark, the shark on
steroids because we're using clot as
well,
>> right?
>> Um so, yeah. No, I I do agree with you.
But on the flip side of that, you know,
they have we also have non software
engineers pushing code to production
because you can just will will an app
into existence now. Y
>> and Lord knows that you know the DevOps
people or you know whatever are going to
also have some problems with how these
things are pushed to prod. So, um, yeah,
I think I think there will be plenty of
stuff to go around, at least for the
next 5 years, but it's definitely going
to be it's definitely moving faster than
I anticipated before. So,
>> Right. Yeah. And then, like you said,
there's so much counter pressure. It's
like there's there's like pressure to
get out code way faster. There's way
more code going out the door. There's
nontechnical people writing so much code
that there's no way the technical code
people can actually review it. So, yeah.
>> And and I think we just don't understand
the code at a depthful level as much
anymore, right? Like I I don't even
know. I wrote an app yesterday and the
day before um and which I'll talk about
eventually on the pod, but I wrote it. I
have no idea what API functions are in
this thing,
>> right?
>> Not not even a single clue. I've never
even looked at the code. I literally
just talked to Claude
>> and it's beautiful and it works exactly
how I want it to work and it's nuanced
and it's lovely, but
>> I have no idea how it works. Yeah.
>> You know, so
>> yeah, that's scary. And that's why you
need some bug hunters to test that out
for you, Justin.
>> Yeah. Seriously. Seriously. Um okay. Um,
so, okay, before we jump into the actual
um, meat for this episode, I got a
little confession, man, because I've
gone on the pod and I've flexed and I've
said, "Your boy is above burnout is
essentially what I've said last time on
the pod." Like, burnout, that's for
those newer full-time hunters, right?
You know, um, got a little burned out,
man. I got a little burned out.
>> It only took three back-to-back events
is all it took.
>> Three back-to-back events overlapping.
And I don't know, man. Freaking Matias
Carlson, man. He goes hard. That
freicker goes hard when he's in a live
hack game event, you know. And
>> so you felt the need to keep up.
>> I felt the need to keep up, you know,
and and so I started putting in these
crazy hours. I got kids. He doesn't have
kids. Screw you, Matias, for not having
kids. Um, and and so it's like, you
know, I just can't can't get the same
volume of hours while still being a
present parent, you know, that I used to
be able to. So I was like sacrificing
the sleep and then Korea hits and I get
all these crazy bugs and I'm jet-lagged
as freick. And then I come back and I'm
like, "Okay, you know, such an awesome
time." And then why am I not wanting to
create content? Why am I not wanting to
hack? Why do I just want to lay here?
You know,
>> dude, it's real. I don't know, man.
>> And and I think it's not just burnout.
Like, it's also probably the fact that
you're you're doing incredible this year
on top of that. You don't have some like
ridiculously large financial need
pushing you to go find those bugs
because you're also doing well. So, it's
kind of like on both ends.
>> It is. It is a little bit on both. But I
feel like, you know, I feel like I've
had so much fun hacking these past like
couple weeks and then all of a sudden,
boom. Like, why is the passion not
there,
>> you know? And then and then, you know,
just needed a little time. It just need
a little time to come back. And it's
back. It's back, baby.
>> Good.
>> All right. Um, I got a bunch of stuff.
You got a bunch of stuff. You want to go
first or should I?
>> Uh, I feel like Yeah, I already went
first with that image, so you got to go
now.
>> Oh, okay. All right. I'm up next.
>> You stole this one. You stole this one
from me, by the way. It was going to be
on my list, and then I get in here and
it's already here and I'm like, "Oh,
come on."
>> All right. Well, I'm going to explain
some really, u crazy [__] on this. So,
uh, you know, if you want to add to it,
you can, but I'm I'm going deep in the
crypto bin here.
>> Perfect. I'm gonna talk more about the
AMP script. So,
>> okay. Well, here why don't you start us
off with AMPScript and then I'll go talk
about the um the the crypto stuff.
>> Yeah, sure. So, um basically
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Uh AMPScript is a custom language
basically. It's like
>> So, so first let's let's intro it. This
is Search Light Cyber's write up on uh
the ghost of encryption pass. How we
read all your emails in Salesforce
Marketing Cloud. So, this is a story of
how they pawned Salesforce Marketing
Cloud through Ampscript, some crypto
stuff, all all that all together, right?
>> Yep.
>> Okay. All right. Go go go with
AMPScript.
>> Uh I I've not like since this was on
yours, I didn't end up like prepping it,
but no, no, no, no. I'm still going to
talk about this because I think it's
really cool. So, one, basically,
AMScript is like serverside templating
language. That's that's mostly what you
need to know. that is specific to SFDC
um Salesforce and specifically to their
marketing cloud and uh I mentioned a
vulnerability oh man like maybe a year
ago that me and me Evan Connley and
Chubs found which used uh one of the
things in this blog post. So if you
scroll down to under foot gun number one
treat content. So there's this really
cool treat as us content which basically
means hey evaluate this
>> and then you can also do uh http getit.
So we hosted more ampscript on shubs's
server and then and then input for our
50 character payload treat as content
http getit his URL. So then it would
basically pull his it would it would
pull more ampscript from his server and
put it inside of that treat as content.
So if you're ever limited in a AMPcript
injection insertion point, you can use
that that backtoback.
>> Nice. Okay. So you kind of
um incurred a double evaluation
scenario, right? You had a template
injection.
>> Yes.
>> And then and then you you needed to get
you know more character space.
>> Yes.
>> And so you hit an HTTP get and then took
the output of that dumped it into street
as content and invoked another template
injection.
>> That's that's exactly right. That's
sick, dude.
>> Yeah, that's why I tweeted about it
because it was so cool. I should have I
should have broken it down like in a
whole bunch of tweets, but actually, let
me see if if I can share it. I can
>> you can track it down. Uh, essentially
the the the um the full flow here just
to give the the listeners, you know,
knowledge about the the article is this
is how they poned uh Salesforce
Marketing Cloud. They found a uh
template injection in the subject line
of emails uh because of double
evaluation and it's using this weird
AMPScript method uh of templates which
is percent percent equals or the lesserk
known version which is um curly bracket
curly bracket equals and that triggers
the AMPScript. So make sure we're adding
these to our template injection
payloads, right? Um, and then you know
using this template injection they're
able to do some crazy crypto stuff which
I'll explain later you know and and it's
a a tangental part of the scope but it
does come back to the template
injection. Um, and yeah really get
access to a bunch of the data in the
system. Um, that's the full flow of
this. And what I want to talk to you
guys uh about in just a sec is this uh
crypto attack that they did later on in
the article. Um,
>> I'll show this. I'll Yeah, I'll show it
super quick and then then I'll switch
back to you. So,
>> it's funny because like obviously
Marketing Cloud is all about marketing,
so it's not in the title, but this was
in the first name.
>> And uh and so the funniest thing was
basically getting an email with the
exfiltration of all of the users in the
database as as your name. So, it's like,
"Hi, Justin and and Douglas and Joseph
and everyone," you know, like it's like
it's like the email is like like a
hundred pages long in your Gmail and
it's just a huge data leak. But anyways,
yeah, it was the first name build and
then we put the extra AMPScript uh stuff
living on shoved the server here and
then it worked like this. So anyways, I
thought people would think that was
cool. Yeah,
>> dude.gg is such a good uh domain.
>> It is. It's cool,
>> man. I I have a good one though. I have
a good one. I'm not going to say it out
loud, but I'm pretty proud of the one
that I have. Um actually, I'll tell you,
Richard, just bleep it. I've got
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> That's pretty freaking great, right?
>> That's very cool. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um okay. Um so let's get back into
this. So uh first you know the the they
get a template injection um via double
evaluation in the subjects or titles of
emails. Um and then they're essentially
what they're trying to do is get um they
realize that these emails are also you
know available
at a domain, right? And so they look at,
you know, they click on the like view in
browser button or whatever and they look
at the the um resulting URL that comes
from that and it has this, you know, QS
parameter that seems to control where,
you know, what email is displayed. So
it's got some encrypted values, right?
>> And they enumerated a bunch of these and
they found out that there's three
primary formats for this. One of them is
a JT that looks pretty solid. The next
one is is a is a, you know, hex. And
then finally, one they find later is
just, you know, raw parameters. Um, I
didn't find that till later, I guess,
though. Um, and my first point that I
wanted to mention here was like this is
a really, you know, you're sniffing for
blood. Your spidey senses should be
tingling here when you see this
implementation change because probably
somebody found something and and they,
you know, sort of fixed it, but they
didn't backdate it, right? Um, and a lot
of times the pipes that glue all of
these things together are the same. So
if they're leaving the old, you know,
format in place, then you might be able
to exploit that even with the newer
format being present.
>> So very interesting.
>> And the way this often looks because I'
I've been a developer before,
>> I feel like a lot of times whenever you
need to support multiple formats, you'll
say like if it's encoded, decode it.
Else treat it as it is. And so honestly
I think I thought what you were going to
say as you approach that that um that
lesson there. I think the lesson is
>> often you should try other formats in
parameters like just across bug bounty
in general across abstack testing. You
know it's kind of the same thing behind
like oh if a JSON post request works you
should try URL form encoded right? It's
like the same thing. It's like if you
see and and I actually don't do this
very often but I'm going to start now.
If you see a B 64 encoded payload, try
decoding it and then still sending it.
Sometimes it still works and then that
might let you do something funky in the
app, right?
>> Yeah. Or, you know, an encrypted
version. One of the things I've seen
many times is, you know, after a little
while the company realizes they screwed
up and switches to this encrypted ID
format, right? And then but they're old
>> backwards compatible.
>> Yeah. They have to be, you know,
backward compatible at least a little
bit, even if it's just for that like
minute when they're doing the migration.
and they forget to never take it away
and uh and you know you can still just
put the unencrypted version of the ID
into that field. Um I've seen that many
times. Um but anyway, going back to the
this whole situation here, they use a
little OS int on this parameter. They
find out what the hex, you know,
encrypted hex values, what it decodes
to. Okay. Uh they find that from a Stack
Exchange reference article.
>> That's awesome.
>> Which is just lovely. And the days of
that unfortunately are are you know few
because uh uh like they've got um you
know stack stack exchange the number of
questions and answers has just like
tanked y
>> um because of AI
>> but um anyway this is the you know the
the format that they have and knowing
that they start sort of doing some bit
flipping on the QS parameter which is
what I've said on the pod many times is
like don't shy away from these crypto
bugs. People implement stuff poorly all
the time in an unauthenticated CBC
algorithm, guys. You do bit flipping and
as long as it doesn't cause like just
flip a couple things here and there and
sometimes you'll see it actually passes
through and then the result of the
decrypted, you know, piece which is in
the response will just look corrupted
like this right here. Um, for those of
you on YouTube, right? It'll just look
like a, you know, question mark or, you
know, a different character or something
like that, right? And that means that
they're using an unauthenticated
CBC, you know, algorithm. Okay? And so
anyway, takeaway there, do bit flipping
when you see encrypted stuff. Okay?
Because you found I found a lot of
padding oracles and I found a lot of
bugs just from doing that. Okay. Um, the
really crazy thing about this exploit
that I didn't I did not know, and this
could just be me not knowing, you know,
about uh this exploit, or it could be
that they came up with this, um, is that
they figured out a way to get the IV for
this CBC by doing this really cool
technique. Okay. And I I'm not going to
lie, I typically nowadays I just read
something, you know, in the articles and
I have no problem coming on the pod and
talking about it. Yeah,
>> I did rehearse the segment
>> because it is it is hard to talk about
like crypto stuff in the audio medium.
Um, and without a visual, you know,
representation, right? I'm going to do
my best. I'm not sure how it's going to
go.
>> I'm going to close I'm going to close my
eyes and test you. I'm not going to read
the article or like I'm just going to
close my eyes and listen to just your
audio.
>> Well, okay, that's great. And and I
would also recommend for anybody that
wants to understand this better, take
this whole article and put it into
Gemini and then just ask it questions
until you understand. Okay. Uh because
that's what I did before to refresh my
memory on this and it and it's lovely.
So what they actually did here, the way
CBC works is that there's an IV
initialization vector that gets um used
with CBC and that is what is exorded
with the cipher text of the first block.
Um and so and that that produces um you
know the output. So what what we they
did here in order to get that IV so that
they could decrypt the rest of it. So I
want you guys to think of it like this.
The the decryption algorithm is you know
a function D and inside of that is
cipher text block one right and then the
output of that function gets exorded
with the IV. Okay. So D of the cipher
text one exord with IV. Okay. So what
they did was they patted out the first
part of their cipher text with eight
null bytes. Okay? So that C that C1
which would be the first block that gets
passed into the the decryption
algorithm, it becomes all null bytes.
Okay. And so the when it gets passed
into the decryption algorithm, the
output of that is just going to be junk.
And that gets um that gets
>> is it predictable junk?
No, it's just junk. Okay.
>> And that gets exorded with the IV. Okay.
So now your junk that that comes from
the null bites tanks the IV for you,
right? Um and then the way that the
second block is is um you know built out
is it takes the the second block which
was our original first block and it
passes that through the decryption
function and it exorses it. It exores it
with the um cipher text of the first
block which is that eight to null
>> by null. Yeah. Which is all null,
>> right? Which you control, right? So then
the result of that is now you have the
raw de decrypted you know of that old
first block. Okay. So now you've got the
old the raw output of the decode from
the first block and you've got the IV
encrypted version from the first block
which is the the normal you know output.
>> So you can get the IV out.
>> So then you you do this with over a
bunch of different valid IDs and you
know a little bit about the plain text
from the Stack Overflow article, right?
and you brute force each bit of the IV
until it matches the the pattern the
output matches the pattern that you know
that the actual plain text has.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. And then over the course of a
bunch of IDs you are able to narrow down
and extract the IV and then using that
IV you can decrypt the first block
originally and get the raw text out.
>> Um
>> so it is it is awesome what what they
did here. I I think that came across
decently. I don't know. Maybe you can
tell me.
>> No, no, no. I think it came across fine.
The question is, were they smart enough
to know that or did they just use AI to
do that?
>> I don't know, man. P, you know, they're
also using Padre, which is a um a uh,
you know, system for doing these padding
oracle CBC related attacks. Um, so
that's cool. And also, shout out to
Padre. I've used it a couple times.
Really useful. Um, very extensible. Love
that about it. Um, and the the other key
thing that I want you guys to take away
here, one, that eight byte, um, null
bite trick is amazing. Um, two is that,
um, definitely, you know, make sure
you're using Padre for these sort of
things. And you, three, you need to make
sure you know, um, the format of the do,
you know, something about the plain text
version of the value you're supposed to
be extracting, right? because that
allows you to sanity check your IV
checks. Um, so anyway, that's my rant.
It's a lot of fun getting, you know, I'm
not an overly mathematical dude. Like, I
don't love math or or crypto or anything
like that. I do love crypto, but like I
don't love the whenever I look at with
those functions with those squiggly
scripts and like, you know, all of that
stuff. I get overwhelmed and I don't
like that. But um you know actually
working on these specific exploits and
finding these bugs is some of the most
gratifying experiences I've had as a
hacker dude. I freaking love it.
>> Well and I think now it's more
accessible than ever before because like
with with LLMs like you can basically
reason through the the the part that you
can't comprehend. So like you can
basically explain you can like reexlain
how you understand it up to the point at
which you don't understand it. And then
the LM can basically be like oh here's
the part you're missing.
>> Right. So yeah.
>> Yeah, totally. Um, so anyway, that's my
>> wrap this up. What do they do with that?
>> That's my that's my rant. Um, once they,
you know, crack that and are able to
they also find an encryption oracle. Um,
and then they're able to use that to uh
craft these arbitrary um, you know,
values that are inside of this encrypted
text and extract all emails and all
email contents from every single person
in all of Salesforce Marketing Cloud
because uh, they use the same um, key
across everything. So, um, and they
asked that that key be not, uh,
>> in the blog post
>> put in the article, and I'm like, "Oh,
geez, that means that [__] is still
active." Um, so I don't know, man. It's
It's tricky. It's tricky.
>> It is tricky.
>> Yeah, let's not go down the disclosure
pipeline.
>> Yeah, I've said I've said my piece
there. Um, yeah, definitely look for,
but I last thing that I wanted to add
was definitely look for all sorts of
variants of crypto stuff, right? Look
for the JDT version. If there's a hex
version, if there's an unencrypted
version, you want to use way more or
whatever to get all of those old
versions of the URLs and audit those old
implementations as well.
>> Sweet. I am gonna talk about skills,
which is kind of funny uh considering
that we did the whole episode on it.
Which actually, by the way, I do want to
take a quick second here. I have gotten
ridiculous amounts of positive feedback
about that. Like I've talked to so many
people who who told me that they just
have been like shilling it to everyone
they know. Uh, and then I just got off a
call with Ethiak because, you know, I'm
an adviser with them. And Andre told me
for this event,
>> um, he wanted to like kind of compare,
you know, their hackbot with with like
just using like cloud code, but he had
never like set up cloud code before and
he said he the only resource he used was
he listened to our episode and and then
that's it. He he just used that to build
out skills and to set it up and then he
used that and he found 17 bugs and he
was like, I know for a fact I wouldn't
have found over half of them without
cloud code. So,
>> pretty sweet, right?
>> Yeah, man. In the last live hacking
event that we were in too, literally all
of the showand tells had a shout out to
Claude Code in them. And I'm like, "Oh
my gosh, this is nuts.
>> It's changing everything." Yeah. And so,
um,
>> he said he said specifically that it
also found a zero day in a Java image
processing library. So, you should reach
out to him because it's pretty cool.
>> Oh my gosh. Holy crap.
>> Um, so I wanted to talk about and I can
share my screen super quickly here. um a
skill optimizer. It is released released
by Tessle. Tessle T SSL is a pretty neat
company. They do like spec as code
stuff, but they have an entire um skill
marketplace or it's called a registry.
Um kind of like skills.sh, but um what
they do is they automatically evaluate
those skills and then rank them the
highest. So, it's kind of a cool skill
registry. Anyways, I'm not trying to
shield that registry. I just love this
skill. They sent out an email about this
skill optimizer skill.
>> Um, it's a little bit meta to talk about
this, but basically just point your
agent at this at this link that we'll
put in the show notes. It's called
Tessle Skill Optimizer. And what it does
is it sets up a whole bunch of
evaluations for your coding agent to see
how likely it is to be invoked and then
and then attempts to improve that
through optimizing the description,
through optimizing the content, through
optimizing the name of it. And bro, blew
my mind. In mine and JD's hackbot, like
over half of them went from like 10%
invocation rate to 85% invocation rate.
And it's because we want though.
>> Well, I'm saying like across the evals
like so this is like the Tesla skill
optimizer attempting to like write
prompts that that where it should invoke
and then testing it. It's not invoking
across 85% of our runs. I'm saying that
like the quality of when it should be
invoked based on what the user wants
went from 10% to 85%.
>> How do you tell it when it should be
invoked?
>> What do you mean?
>> Like like so why am I trusting this
skill optimizer to know
>> because your description already has
when it should be invoked, right? Like
you already have that in your skill in
the description.
>> Okay. So it's looking at my description.
It's saying here are a bunch of test
cases which align with that description.
Yes.
>> And then it's saying, does it match the
description that I just generated all
these emails from?
>> No. Then it's firing those. It's firing
all of those tests it just wrote based
on what when you want to invoke it
>> and seeing how many it invokes on
>> and seeing how many invokes on, right?
And so then it came out to like 10 or
15% for a bunch of my skills.
>> Wow. Okay.
>> And so then then it attempts to fix it
and then it reruns them.
>> Interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> Interesting. Anyways, my whole point of
this is the the main point which is
which is like uh really the the the
lowhanging fruit that I think everyone
in the audience should check is their
description front matter field. So as
skills in markdown there's a thing
called front matter at the top right
it's like the the title the description
like references or author or something
right
>> the description field at least in cloud
code and I think also in codeex is what
gets passed to the agent assuming that
you're you know your main prompt isn't
so long that it gets truncated anyways
the description field there is what
actually gets um sent to the agent so
that's all it has besid has the title
and the description to decide when to
invoke right that description field in
markdown is not uh multi-line. And so if
you have description colon and then new
line and then you have some descriptions
or you have description colon the first
line and then you go down to new lines,
all of those extra lines are not getting
picked up because markdown does not do
multi-line by default. You have and so
this is what it fixed on a ton of ours.
So So here's what you want. Here's what
everyone wants. You want you want the
description colon and then greater than
dash.
After that, it'll it'll pick up every
single line. It'll massively impact
include it. Let me actually I'm just
going to do a new doc and show everyone
what I'm talking about. Just super quick
for anyone watching on line.
>> Yeah, dude. That's crazy though because
that means like half of your descript,
you know, everything but the first line
of your description might not be making
it into claude, right?
>> Which means it may not be triggering
these whenever you you need them to be.
Right.
>> Right. Exactly. So let's say you have a
I have a skill called reszo skill,
right? And the description here
>> is like this. You know, normally I would
say like I want you to invoke when you
see a 403, right? The only thing that
was going to the agent was this.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> And I think in a bunch of mine, I had
something like this
>> and I thought that this and uh for the
listeners basically I had something that
was like description colon just greater
than. And I think this does work in some
markdown formats, but this does not work
for the way cloud code works. So, you
want it to be like this. Description
colon greater than dash. Yep. That's
exactly what you want. And that will
that will fix all It's a really weird
format. I've never seen it before. That
is what you want. And it will fix all of
your skill invocations.
>> Okay. I I I also thought when you said
greater than, you probably meant less
than. No, he actually means greater
than.
>> Greater than dash
>> description greater than dash. Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Okay. So, a couple things here. It
also fixed for many of mine camel case
into underscore case. I don't know why,
but I think that it got higher
invocation rates with that. So, if your
skill names are camo case, switch them
to snake case. And
>> I freaking hate that.
>> Why?
>> Cuz I You're a camel case, bro.
>> Yeah, dude. Totally. All day.
>> Oh, don't me. Snake is so much better.
>> It It inflates the size of things. And
it's so readable with camel case.
>> No, it's way more readable with
underscores. You're so used to reading
with spaces. But but it's I
>> I'm a Python bro and we got to name all
of our functions.
>> Don't freaking tell me you're a Python
bro. I am a Python bro 2.7 back in the
day that was the standard and then they
changed it.
>> Okay. Well, listen here. At least tell
me you're a twospace Python bro and not
a fourspace Python bro.
>> Get get out. Get out. Get out. You're
you are fired.
>> Do you actually use four spaces or do
you use tabs? Please tell me you're not
tabs.
>> I use tabs. I use tabs, bro. I use tabs.
>> And you're on Windows and you're on
>> I don't use anything now because I I
>> This is This is Maybe this is one of
those situations where, you know,
opposites attract, right? Where we're
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay. All right. Anyway, so you're
saying somehow for some reason Claude is
wrong and bad and it wants you to use
underscores. Is that correct?
>> Yes. Yeah. So skill name should be
underscores or at least in my testing it
it uh invokes better when you do that.
And the very last thing I was going to
mention is some of my skills had the
word claude in them. Apparently that is
like a huge no no. So if you have like I
had a skill called DM other clauds and I
would allow my cloud locally to message
my cloud on my VPS.
>> I changed it to DM other agents and all
of a sudden it like massively improved.
I think that the word claude is like a
reserved word and so it either gets like
parsed or or doesn't view it as well or
something. Um, yeah. I didn't look into
the nitty-gritty details, but yeah.
>> Interesting. That is That is pretty
cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
I I'm just going to take a breather for
a second, you know, from that that
massive disappointment that just uh, you
know, hit me. Um, and I guess we'll talk
about It's all right. You know,
Watchtowers got me covered. They're
going to they're going to, you know, get
me focused on this next write up. Okay.
>> So, um, this next write up is the
internet is falling down.
>> Falling down. falling down. Uh, and it
is none other than the C panel off
bypass, which is breaking everything.
So, by the time this episode airs, you
guys probably have already like digested
all of this, but I did want to walk
through a couple of the um, beautiful
pieces about this exploit. Um,
one,
it's Pearl. So, um, you know, when
you're looking at the, um, the, you
know, actual code here, it really helps
a lot, right? And, you know, sometimes
we run into these situations where we're
trying to reverse engineer something and
it's like a binary and it's just such a
pain. Um, I will say like I've I've
hacked on a couple things that are Pearl
or um, you know, Python and it's just so
much more fun. Uh that being said, I
know for a fact a lot of good hackers
have looked at this and not found this
bug. Um so really cool that um you know
this vulnerability was discovered and it
this is you know watchtower reverse
engineering it um reverse engineering
the patch. Um so here is the situation.
um they look at the patch, they figure
out that they find this beautiful
comment that says filter against slashrn
uh from values before writing kills the
crlf injection primitive against the on
disk key value record format and that is
the most in-depth message I have ever
seen in a batch in my entire life. Um
>> like it almost gives it away. Yeah, it
totally like really I mean not not
totally gives it away but I mean it
gives you puts right to the meat you
know like the primitive that you need.
>> So the situation here was that um part
of the off material was being parsed and
then written in the um file system to a
file. And guys I just freaking love
this. Let me see if I can find the file
uh right here. Right. um var cPanel
sessions raw and then the session ID and
I just love this [__] guys this is
exactly what I'm talking about like you
we've got to thoroughly assess these
systems and and understand how the full
offflow works right is it actually
writing files to disk you know with with
your authentication material and in this
scenario it really is and that should
just being bing um you know in your head
when you see something like that uh and
the way that they had to make this
exploit work was uh They actually used
two different authentication methods.
One from a cookie and one from an O
header. So that's another really
beautiful thing is like look at
different routes for authentication.
Long story short, by combining the
cookie and the authentication header,
they're able to smuggle a SLR/n in and
get that written to disk uh in this
session descriptor file which is SLR/n
delimited. Okay, so now they're
injecting arbitrary attributes into a
session. Um, and they were able to
establish a pre-author session by uh
submitting an invalid um, you know,
username and password, right? Um,
and so that was really cool. Now they're
injecting attributes into there, but
they keep hitting these roadblocks and I
just I love the way Watchtower writes,
dude. They're like, you know,
they're like, and that's that's it. Is
this the big red button time? You know,
and then they're they submit it and
they're like, [__] you know, like
what's going on? Uh, why isn't this
working? Why are we always treated so
badly is what they say?
Um, and then they hit another roadblock
with their 403. Um, and there's like a
cached version of this, you know, r/n
delimited file that is loaded into JSON.
And the endpoints prefer the cached
version. So now they've got to find, you
know, a primitive in the system that uh
forces a reload from from the the raw
file rather than the cache. And then
they finally find that and and they make
it work. And then they keep going and
then they they run it again and they hit
a 403 again, right? And um so they just
keep going and keep going and keep going
and do we deserve this.
>> Yeah, you'd think we were done at this
point, you know. Um give us strength. I
I love these articles, man. Um but uh
anyway, as they continued down with the
the exploit, they figured it out. They
got the cash invalidated. they inject in
injected another, you know, value into
the um file which bypassed a a um
defense in depth measure where they did
the password check again and finally
they got the full off bypass. Um and I
just think that's such an example of
like force of will in these exploits,
right? Obviously, if they're patching
it, there's something that's been done
here, but they are persevering, running
into blockade after blockade after
blockade and getting the full O bypass,
which is freaking
>> I think there are lots of moments when
companies trying to reverse patches
>> uh end up finding tangental bugs because
like because like that first primitive
was there and they got that easily, but
then they got blocked and then they had
to find another primitive that isn't
exactly clear in the patch. And then
when they find one, it's like, oh, was
that actually a different route to the
vulnerability?
>> Yeah, I bet, you know, who knows what
the actual thread actor was using or the
original finder, you know. Um,
>> so very cool. And actually sort of
mentioning that, um, Search Light Cyber
also did a write up on this O bypass and
they released a C panel um, a high
integrity, you know, high fidelity
check, which is what they always do,
which I freaking love them for, right?
is they release these like really quick
and easy little scripts. You can point
at a a host and say, "Hey,
>> is the is this vulnerable?" Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Awesome. They're so cool for that. Um
and they added two things to this one.
Um they added uh the way a third way of
accessing this. You know, there were two
ways mentioned in the main article, but
there's actually a third way through um
a another port that's open on cPanel
where you can hit this super weird
reverse proxy rule and it and it um hits
one of the management ports um in the
back end. So there's actually you can't
just block off the management ports in
the WHM service uh to to patch this bug.
You have to also patch uh you know block
off um a third one. And I'm trying to
figure out which one it is. I don't have
it right in front of me right now, but
there's another service that you need to
block off as well. Um, and then finally,
they also mentioned that, hey, if you're
checking for that invalid password to
get the the pre-auth session that I
mentioned, if you're doing that on route
every time, it's going to lock everybody
out. Uh, so here's
>> it. Is it just crazy to me that they
keep this stored on disk in anyways?
Like I just would assume this would
always be in a database in like every
app.
>> Yeah, dude. I don't know. I mean, that
does give me legacy vibes. I know PHP
also does some stuff like this, so maybe
it's just a, you know, Pearl PHP legacy
thing. Um, but yeah, I think it is a
little whack. And um and yeah, just
wanted to shout out the um the SL Cyber
team there for releasing the scanner and
also finding some really good um other
mechanisms that don't cause lockout uh
to confirm that the vulnerability exists
on your target. So we'll we'll uh we'll
link that in the description if you guys
want to check that out as well.
>> Perfect. So I um wanted to give just a
little bit of feedback from the last
episode. Mhm.
>> Obviously, I know we talked about a
little bit at the beginning. Um, I've
been doing like u hacker advisory board
for hacker one and then also bug crowd
just here recently because I think they
bring me in because of the AI knowledge
and stuff and then they're just all
struggling, right? I mean, all the all
the programs and platforms are
struggling with this volume.
>> And so, I kind of thought it would be
neat if for program managers who are
listening and also platforms. I just
wanted to bring one like kind of key
piece of advice that I thought of in the
most recent HAB meeting. Um, it's
nothing confidential or anything, but I
just think that for companies that are
struggling and for the fact that when
platforms are struggling, if they
basically gave this option to all of
their programs,
it would reduce the total traffic and
total volume by like, you know, 50% or
something crazy and allow everyone to
catch up and then allow us to get back
to have faster triage and faster bounty
times, right? Cuz it's hard on
everybody. they feel behind on their
SLAs's. We feel frustrated because
they're taking forever to get stuff
triaged and to get b and payouts out.
And then when you're waiting a long time
in triage, sometimes the bug gets fixed
and then that's really frustrating, hard
to handle
>> happening.
>> So, so I think that my um I just have
this like one little concise pitch that
I think would be really beneficial. If
you're a program manager or you're a CSM
for a platform and you've got companies
that are struggling, just offer them
like this like uh plate, this like
platter of options. It's like here's the
things you can do and you should do some
of them. You could take your program
private or you know I don't love that
idea but this is just one option. You
could require you could require videos
for for for and we talked about this
even like you know
>> you could require videos for your um
reports. You could require higher signal
so you could bump up your signal
requirements. I've never seen a company
like bump it to like five or six on
hacker one but that'd be kind of
interesting to see what happens. You
could allow trusted or verified people
only. So you kind of like, you know,
disallow people who are not like
verified in the system.
>> Um, and actually I just saw James Kettle
is talking about our episode. He said he
really liked it, the most recent episode
um, in Discord. And he said that what
they've done for the Porsche program is
they've left highs and criticals at the
same payouts, but they've reduced the
bounties on their lows and mediums.
>> And we're seeing that a lot actually.
>> I think that's kind of reasonable. Um,
just because like those are going to be
harder to get to these days. Um, some of
the out output that I've learned from
the Hacker Advisor Board meetings is
that there's kind of like an exponential
curve of like unfixed bugs. It's not
fully exponential yet, but it looks like
an exponential curve with the number of
like outstanding reports across all
across all um programs.
>> And so what that tells me is they're
having a hard time fixing it as fast as
the bugs are coming in, right? And I
think we knew that would be the case
this year as everyone's scaling up their
hacks. like as all of this low and
medium hanging fruit gets found, the
developers of these companies can't keep
up. And so I think that one way you can,
you know, kind of cut down on the lows
and mediums and also save on your
security budget because you might be
like be literally running out and like
struggling to get back more um finances
to cover those is to either, you know,
stop paying lows and mediums, which I
don't love, or reduce the the payouts on
the lows and mediums. But I think
Justin, you would definitely say try to
protect your highs and crits because
one, that's where the real impact is and
two that like if you if you reduce
those, one, you might not actually get
hackers looking at your program anymore
because right now what I'm deciding to
point my hackbot at is really at like
what is the highest payout I can get?
Like what is the critical payouts? So
you're not going to get, you know, as
protected, but also it's just like what
matters to us. So
>> yeah. Yeah. I certainly think that we
are in a different environment than we
were in when I said, you know, praising
the low and mediums, right? I, you know,
you're worried, I'm worried for the
whole ecosystem in general.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and I think that if they have to,
you know, make some changes for lows and
mediums, I understand that.
>> I'm finding a lot more highs and crits
than I used to because of the hack bots,
right?
>> Um,
>> so I'll I'll say that. Would I like to
see it? Absolutely not. I would love to
not see it, you know. Uh but because the
Abbots are also freaking good at finding
mediums, you know, lows and mediums.
>> Um I like your signal idea. I'm looking
at the leaderboard right now. There are
a lot of people in the top 100 that
have, you know, below five signal.
>> Really?
>> I was kind of thinking five would be the
cut off. The top 30 pretty much all have
above um six signal. I think ironically
today is new I think is at like 5.393 or
something like that. Um, but you know,
you could make your cut off at like
five,
>> right?
>> You know, or something like that and
that might help. That will cut out some
of the top hackers, which is crazy. Um,
but that's a part of the game, I guess.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, the one that I like the most though
is uh requiring video PSC
>> and uh
or paying for submission.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Those are the ones that I like. I think
that those are great ideas and that
would really boost the ecosystem a lot.
>> They implemented that on hack and proof.
I think it's just unlikely with the
speed and pace of development at Hacker
One and Bug Crowd that that would
actually come out. Um I think it would
be more likely they could convert like
your signal or rep into like points you
can spend and then if you run out of
those
>> um you get it. That's a good idea. The
the other idea I had, Justin, I think
you might really like this one because
it doesn't penalize people like you and
I,
>> is that um you could do a a a system
where you get a bounty reducer
percentage based on the amount of slop
you have or or or maybe you even get an
increase if you if you never push any
slop. So like if you start getting NAS,
you get like a 10% uh bounty reduction,
then a 20%, then a 30%, right? And so it
doesn't ever leave us in this situation
where a person finds a bug and they
can't submit it because I think that
that often leads to like bad public
disclosures because they get mad and
they're posting on Twitter and it's like
because their signal's too low, right?
It's like what am I supposed to do? How
am I supposed to report it? And like you
end up in these situations where it's
that. But I think that if if it's like
no, you can still submit it, but you're
going to get a 50% bounty because you've
been like wasting so much of our time.
It kind of makes the balance between
time and effort for them to triage more
reasonable.
>> That doesn't really decrease the triage
burden though. Like I mean it will over
the long term but it doesn't stop the
bleeding right now. I feel like we're in
a tourniquet situation here really where
we need to like stop the bleeding right
now like you said right and that's why I
think hacken proofs dollar to submit a
bug no one gives a [__] about a dollar
right you know if you're submitting a
bug right if you are submitting a real
bug that has the potential to be paid
thousands of dollars you don't give a
[__] about a dollar
>> well they did notice that $2 one and $2
uh penalties don't reduce slop but when
you get to five it does reduce it. Yeah.
So there was there was cut off points.
They did at $2 and it it didn't stop
slop at all. At at five it stopped like
80% and by like $8 or $10 it stopped
like 100%.
>> So they should just do $5 is my point.
Or
>> refunded, right?
>> Yeah. And it's refunded if it's a valid
bug. Yeah. But then also you could even
scale it based on region of the world.
And then of course there's like VPN
issues and all that. But I do think that
like you know $5 for a new hacker they
might struggle or not really want to or
something. But yeah, it's still five
bucks. Yeah, I think that I think that
we would maybe see grants or something
like that in that situation where um you
know if you get a vouch or something
like that from somebody in the system.
>> Yeah.
>> That you are going to not submit [__]
>> then you know you get a voucher for like
50 bucks in free submissions or
something like that. I think that'll be
pretty interesting. I like it.
>> I like it. It doesn't it doesn't affect
it doesn't affect the real players. It
will affect new new players.
But good luck new players moving into
the system. I mean, there really is a
lot of benefits to you right now with
Claude and and you can, you know, get a
lot of things explained to you. Um, but
there's also a lot of competition. So,
it's it's an interesting interesting
time.
>> Um, all right. Am I up next?
>> Well, actually, just one more thing on
that. I think it's actually a really uh
key insight. I I work with a third world
hacker as like somebody that I sometimes
collaborate with
>> and um he will we we've made like you
know tens of thousands of dollars
together over over just this just this
year
>> and and um the way that he brings a lot
of value to me and that we end up
collaborating so um in such a beneficial
way is because he'll be like, "Hey, I'm
in this program. I'm looking at this
thing. It's kind of interesting. will
you put your cloud on it? And I it's
basically no time to me. I'm like,
"Yeah, sure. Here, cloud, take a look at
this." And then it finds something and
then we go back and we find stuff and
and he has cloud code, too. But I think
that just like the my system or my setup
for some reason will find stuff that his
doesn't. And so if you are if you are a
new person, I think reaching out to like
some top hackers and being like, "Hey,
you know, I've been looking at this
thing." Because even top hackers with a
lot of hack bots that are scaling, we
still can't look at everything all the
time. So, if you find something
interesting, a way that you can make
sure you get a good uh or like you you
make sure you're not leaving stuff
hanging is by reaching out to some top
hunters that you know and being like,
"Hey, I found this lead. Do you mind to
like take a look?"
>> Yeah, that's that makes sense. Um I
don't know that I can deal with any more
influx of that. Uh maybe send it send it
to Joseph.
>> I don't know. I'm pretty busy, too. But
yeah, there's there's plenty of people
in the in the critical thinkers chat
that are like very highly talented. Just
look for a collaborator. Yeah,
>> absolutely. Um, all right. Speaking of,
uh, you know, collaborators of yours,
um, we have, uh, an article by XSS
doctor, um, with XSS doc and Monke's new
startup, Star Strike. Um, they are, they
released an article called achieving
deterministic prompt injection through
client side feedback loops. And I wanted
to run you guys through this really
quick because I think this shows the
doc's mastery of client side concepts.
um and really beautiful weaponization of
them. Okay. Yeah. So the TLDDR of this
article is that there is a um Q
parameter on a chatbot which allows you
to do prompt injection
>> 20 30 50% of the time that will result
in XSS. That is not great for triage
because what's going to happen is
they're going to click it and it's not
going to work and then they're going to
NMI you and it's going to waste your
life.
>> Yep.
>> And it's not a a great exploit, right?
you know, it it sometimes uh people will
decrease the bounty for nondeterministic
AI exploits.
>> So, what they cover in this um in this
article is how to make it more
deterministic.
Um there's also a post message based
race condition in here which utilizes
the technique that we discussed on uh
the um hackalong that we did on Adobe
not too long ago in the critical
thinking discord where you pop up a
small window and keep that in the front
of the victim window uh to make sure
that you're that both of the the victim
window and the attacker window are in
focus or in view which limits the uh
rate limiting on post messages. is being
sent across origin. So that's a a good
technique uh that I wanted to pass off
to you guys. Uh but the whole setup here
is um Doc pops open a new window. This
is the attacker's window. And in the
background, he multiple times sends the
prompt injection. Sends it once, waits
10 seconds. If he does not get a call
back from the XSS firing, he will
reinject the prompt again and then wait
another 10 seconds. Doesn't get a call
back, send it again. Right? And so 30
seconds of sitting on the page, you
have, you know, a massive chance of
getting this exploit to actually work.
Okay.
>> So cool.
>> Um,
>> very cool client side feedback loops.
Really good idea. Great way to increase
the um, integrity of your exploits,
whether it be uh, prompt injection
related stuff or race conditions or both
like this situation is. Um, I I did want
to mention one little bit here uh, a
modification that I had to this article.
Um he solves a problem here and maybe he
has a good reason for doing this. I
don't know. But he solves a problem here
by uh of the victim iframe that is
receiving the race condition. Uh he
solves that not having a reference to
the attacker's window by making the
parent the opener of the attacker's
window as well. So it's a mutual opener
situation. So the attacker's window is
an opener of the victim window and the
victim window is an opener of the
attacker's window. Um this is possible.
You can read it how to how to do it in
the article. Um he says the reason for
that is that the victim had no uh window
reference to the attacker page. Um
however the attacker had a reference to
the victim page. Um and my solution to
this would have been a little bit
different. My solution would have been
to just use the post message event
source. So whenever you send a a a post
message to an iframe um there will be an
event object that gets passed into the
post message handler and that event
object has a source uh attribute. That
source is a window reference to the
frame that created the post message that
is being sent.
>> So I would have
>> So that statement is actually wrong.
It's not that there's no reference. It's
just that well at this current time it
doesn't have a reference but as soon as
you send a post message in in trigger
the XSS if you send another post message
then uh you can register an event
handler to snag that post message and
then uh log the event source and then
shoot back out to the attackers page. Um
that's how I would have solved the
problem. Uh just wanted to show that out
there. But I think this trick of having
mutual um opener
>> opener
>> uh is also a really cool trick. uh for
you guys to know as well and it's really
beautifully displayed here on their blog
with um you know a graph of this whole
attack. So great work by um XSS doc and
Mon at Starlight or Starstrike.ai.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Good work.
>> All right, we are low getting lower on
time but we're still doing fine. I just
wanted to mention to everyone u GPT5
or sorry 55
GPT5. So, I've got two uh links I'm
going to show. Um
>> well, actually, one, can we just
>> tweet about SLGO, bro? Is that as OP as
it sounds?
>> It's so OP. It's the exact solution that
you wanted to run overnight.
>> You just give it a goal of like find
five crits and then even if it finds two
crits, it'll just keep going until like
it literally will just work until it
reaches its success condition. And it's
so good. Like to me, it almost I hate
this.
>> How does this not exist in cloud code,
dude?
>> Great question. But it it uh to me it's
like the final cheat code that makes
this the barrier to entry to this
basically zero. So let me tell you why I
was finally convinced to buy a codeex uh
sub and let me tell you how it went. So
I'm going to share my screen on this
LinkedIn post.
>> There's one of these that I agree with.
>> DMs first.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so actually that's true. I always do
that on X. I always show my DMs and they
have to scrub it. So, this is a very
confusing chart and I also think it may
have been cherrypicked, but it still was
enough to convince me. So, this says
GPT55 delivers the best performance
we've seen to date. For listeners, I'm
sorry, this is confusing, but there's
basically two lines. There's a white
line, which is white box, and it
compares GP5, Gemini 3, Opus 45, 52, and
Opus 46. I don't know why they didn't
keep the white line going for the latest
models, but anyways, because like we
have no we have no idea on this white
line how Opus 47 or GPT55 do. But the
point is that when it comes to white box
testing, the cloud models are better.
You can just tell by Opus 46 having a
huge increase here. Now, I will say the
Y-ax on this is really dumb. It's
vulnerabilities found before first miss.
What do they mean by miss? What do they
mean by miss? Does that mean like before
it didn't find a bug or or that means it
submitted a false positive? So they
picked a really obnoxious y-axis. But uh
anyways, this blackbox line is what
convinced me. So they have a dotted
blackbox line. So this is like, you
know, again, it's just like the tracking
of the vulnerabilities found before miss
across Opus 45 all the way through Opus
47 and then GPT5. And when you look here
at Opus uh 46, it's like a And also, why
is this not on the like how can you have
how can you have less than one
vulnerability? Is this like a 4.9?
>> No, no, that's five, bro. That's five.
>> Yeah, it Well, they missed the mark.
Anyways, my gosh, my whole point is
Opus46 is much lower than GPT55. And so,
and then they they posted this other
thing which I'm not uh
>> Well, okay. Okay, let me let me let me
comment on that really quick. Can you
pull it back up for a sec? So
essentially what we're seeing here is
Opus 4.6 is is finding um like four
vulnerabilities before first miss on
average and with GPT 5.5 this is in a
blackbox context it jumps up to like
eight or nine.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so it almost doubles right which is
insane.
>> Yeah. And and they obviously you know
are people who I relatively well trust a
little bit on like how to like like Expo
should be able to evaluate these models,
right? They've been doing this for like
three years at this point. they should
be able to evaluate these models and
they and they did more than just this.
So I'm going to read this other post
which I again and this one I'm even more
skeptical of but um we'll read it
anyways. Albert Ziggler, the head of AI
at Expo says GPT55 without access to
source code is a better hacker than most
previous models with source code. Okay,
he says most here. I thought he said
than open 6, which is what I just
straight up didn't believe, but I think
this is definitely true. I I think that
statement is definitely true. If you
assume he's talking about like GPT54 or
GPT53 or or other companies, I don't
think it is better than 46 or 47 with
code like with white source white box
code,
>> but in general, so anyways, this this
convinced me to try it, Justin. Within
the first 30 minutes, it found three P1s
of me running GPT. No, I'm not kidding
at all. Now, I will say it it did have a
little bit of advantage. It was a fresh
invite program on Buck. like it was like
a new program that just dropped. So, you
know, take take that with a grain of
salt, but still that was faster and more
efficient than what I had seen for Opus.
Now, for anyone wanting to try it,
here's all I did. I sim linked my cloud
MD to agent MD from Claude to do.codex
folder. Then, I just had Claude Code sim
link all of the folders in the in the
skills folder to the codec skills folder
and then just ran it. I got and I and I
am cyber approved or whatever, but I got
no rejections. I I used SlashGold to run
this overnight. It found like lots of
other bugs. My my intuition is that it's
like 10 or 20% better than 47 and 46 um
at blackbox testing. And Justin, I like
didn't run out of tokens. I like I had
one/goal that ran for 14 hours. And then
when I checked, I'd only used like like
15% of my weekly usage stats. Um,
meaning that I could obvious that that
was like 130th of the monthly stats for
the $200 a month. Anyways, it's wildly
effective. I think people should
basically be building their systems to
be usable by both cloud code and codeex.
And I think that, you know, in the past
I was like, "No, cloud code, cloud code,
cloud code." Now, I think it's totally
reasonable to use either system and
you'll be highly successful.
>> Dang, dude. That's crazy. That's crazy.
I I I will say also, you know, with just
4.6, I also had a target on Bug Crowd
this past week that uh is is a fresh
fresh program. So, I wonder if I wonder
if we're going to dupe. Uh hopefully
not.
>> No, it's not. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, you can bleep that, Richard. Yes,
please.
>> Um Yeah. Okay. So, we're good. But, uh I
literally I was sitting here with my
friends, right? And we're like, let's
just kick this off. Let's see how it
goes. I kid you not, within 15 minutes,
it had an a like a JWT takeover. Yeah.
JWT forging bypass. Bro,
>> you uh you know, I need to actually I
need to audit your um JWT skill if you
don't mind.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I got you. Um, so
>> I was I was saying that as a joke cuz I
want to steal it.
>> Oh, well, dude, you shared me so much. I
I DM you all the time. I'm like, tell me
exactly how you do this.
>> Oh, you did do that yesterday. Actually,
when you did that yesterday, I was like,
he's really sussing me out here.
>> I'm sussing you out. Well, I'm also
taking a different approach, though, so
we can compare and contrast. So, um, the
question I asked you yesterday, I did it
different than you and JD. So, um, we'll
we'll we'll compare notes on that a
different time. Um, all right. I've got
one last, uh, write up. This one is
super sick. Uh, save the best for last
in my opinion here. Um, freaking love,
dude. He's such a good hacker. Uh, and
anytime I read anything by him, uh, I am
floored. So this is uh
>> actually wait just for our listeners
really quickly if you don't know Rio
talk obviously we've mentioned him a ton
in the podcast but this guy was like
basically fresh in the bug bounty scene
>> and he came to Defcon and did like you
know H1 405 wait H147
>> H172
>> 702 H172 and just won it got MVH
>> at like 18
>> yeah as like an 18-year-old. So anyways,
statistical skill level here.
>> Anyway, absolute beast. Um, I've
mentioned on the pod, I think he is the
closest thing that we have to AI,
>> you know, like like just just seeing him
consume minified JavaScript code like a
book.
>> Like just I I've never seen anything
like it at any before to be perfectly
honest. Um anyway, so without hyping him
up too much, flat uh you know, really
flat security in Japan really snagged a
good one when they got here. And this
write up is on their blog. Um and it is
remote code execution on Google Cloud
with a single directory deletion. Um and
this is on Google Cloud's Looker. Um so
Looker is a business intelligence
platform. Um I've actually seen other
bugs in this, so probably a good place
to hunt. um he is able to get a
self-hosted version so he can reverse
engineer it and he's looking at how all
of this uh stuff works here in Ruby. Um,
and the the TLDDR of the situation is he
finds a way to um delete an arbitrary
directory from within his own repository
uh via a um you know confusion in the
validate path name function uh for
deleting the the directory.
>> Yeah.
>> And he's able to use that to delete
the.getit git repo for uh one of his
projects that he's uploaded.
>> Yeah.
>> And then he says something that just
freaking blew my mind and that everybody
here should be paying very very very
close attention to. Okay. Since it is
possible to trick Git into using forged
git configurations if the doggget
directory is corrupt or deleted, the
validate named dur method checks the
directory to be deleted, includes.git,
and raises an error if it does. Okay, so
you're not supposed to be able to delete
the.git directory. Interesting.
>> And then he just he just kind of slips
it in there since it is possible to
trick Git into forging as everybody
knows it. It's possible to trick Git
into using forge git configurations if
the.git directory is corrupted or
deleted blahy blah blah blah. I went
back and I was like, wait, what? So if I
can delete the.git repo from my my or
the.git folder from my repository
folder.
>> Yeah. and you run command inside that
folder,
>> you can get RC. This is essentially what
this reduces to.
>> Wow. Do you know do you know how many
>> coding sand like AI coding sandbox
features we've tested that that might be
relevant to?
>> Yeah, dude. A ton. And and so
essentially he explains the reason for
this. Um, if the git directory is
deleted, the next git command executed
against this repository will fail to
find the git directory and it will look
for git configurations in the work tree
directory instead.
>> Wow.
>> Therefore, if the work tree contains the
files that resemble the contents of a
doggget, git assumes that you are in let
me where is
>> are you kidding?
>> Yeah, git assumes that you are in thegit
directory and we'll just load these
files straight from the the root of the
work tree. So, let me just explain how
this work.
>> So, what's the what's the folder you
want to put it in? Tell me. I need I
need the juice right now, Justin. So,
>> yeah, dude. I mean, look at this graph
that's on the screen.
>> Yeah.
>> Look at this on the screen.
>> You can put it in any of those. Oh, you
just put it You just put it straight in
it. It thinks it's already inside.Get,
>> right? So, literally, it thinks it's
already inside. So, they're running a
git command from the the root directory
of the repository. Typically, it says,
"Okay, let me look at the.git, you know,
folder. You know, if it's not there, oh
[__] I guess we're inside the repo
already." So it just read tries to read
config right and then treats it
as.git/config. So this is the whole
situation right you guys can't we can't
upload you know malicious.git
folders to git right that's the you know
that's where a lot of security in all of
these systems relies on thegit repo is
sacred right and if I can check that to
make sure there aren't hooks or whatever
you know we're all good right but then
if you can delete that.getit git repo.
It'll just treat the config file that's
in the root of your repo as the git
config and you can register hooks and
then you're set.
>> Dude, we've got a week. Can we go look
for this in and
>> uh as soon as this calls out.
>> We're late, bro. We're late. I think
this this thing shipped in March.
>> Yeah, March.
>> Yeah, but I mean the number of people
that saw this and then drew the same
conclusion to us is probably pretty low.
I mean, people just read their eyes
glaze over. This is good stuff. Anyway,
>> honestly, is this vulnerability in git?
>> No, this is just
>> Are you sure?
>> No. No. There there's some code branch
inside git, inside git code that is
saying if.git is not there, look in the
current directory. And I think that that
is probably a vulnerability. I think it
should always make sure it's in agit.
>> I don't know, man. Maybe I'm
misunderstanding it, but uh that seems
like the way that git is just going to
work. I can definitely see the GitHub
team being like, "Nah, bro." Like, this
is how it works, you know? So anyway,
then it's trivial. Okay. No, I'm sorry.
It's not trivial from there. Let me let
me let me also give another shout out to
Genius. So now he's got the config file
in there, right? Um and and so let me
explain.
He the way he got the the directory to
delete was actually not deleting the git
directory at all. He deleted the entire
repository directory, right? The entire
one, including his own config files,
right? But the way that the delete
recursive works in Ruby, you know, it
will recursively go in and delete all
the files.
>> Yeah.
>> So he he created a folder that's massive
that has a ton of files in it, right?
That's going to take the delete after
the.getit and before his config, right?
So, so what'll happen is this. He'll
say, "Delete the whole repository
folder." And he'll say, "Okay, great.
Going to recursively delete." It goes in
there, deletes the dotgit, right? So now
we're in a vulnerable state.
>> Then it finds massive folder, you know,
and then 1500 million, you know, files,
uh, you know, nested within that. It
goes deep. It goes deep. It goes deep.
It goes deep. It's deleting files. It's
deleting files. It's taking forever. In
the meantime, Riota is hitting another
endpoint that runs git status on that
same folder in the middle of deletion.
>> Oh gosh. triggers the config for um you
know the
>> he's literally an AI Justin
>> dude triggers the FS monitor hook and
then runs arbitrary commands on the the
Google prod
>> he's a robot
>> server
>> freaking beautiful man I love it and he
explains the nuance of like the XF4 file
system and how um the Ruby file utils
rm-rf uh you know recursively deletes
stuff it it was beautifully done but the
concept is that and it was just chef's
kiss, dude.
>> Yeah, that's insane.
>> Yeah. And then he explains even the full
privilege escalation um inside of Google
Kubernetes cluster as well um because
he's able to check the service account
in /wiron/secs
kubernetes ioservice account and found
some excessive permissions that they're
able to update secrets for all the other
Kubernetes clusters as well which
results in full privilege escalation. So
>> wow.
>> Yeah,
>> that's you're right. You did save the
best for last.
>> That was a freaking beautiful bug,
right? The race condition, the get like
confusion.
>> Yeah, dude. It's just beautiful.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, man.
>> Yeah. Shout out to Tuck and flat. Um,
all right. You got anything else or is
that a wrap? Right on time.
>> Let me check the notes. No, it looks
good. I'm done. Yep.
>> All right, dude. That's the pod. Peace.
>> Thanks.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.